CONTACT

Watford, WD24 07828 716124 joedigitalmedia@gmail.com Joeobrienmedia.com

JOE O'BRIEN

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER

JOEOBRIENMEDIA.COM

SKILLS

Javascript & REACT
Redux / React Hooks
Wordpress
HTML5 / CSS3 & SASS
Adobe Photoshop
Microsoft Excel & Office
Film Booking & Cinema
Team Management/ Customer Service

PROFILE

I am a passionate, multi-skilled individual, looking to take the next step in my career. With a 1.1 Masters in Interactive Media, , several years of freelance and professional web development experience, and 5 years of cinema industry experience under my belt, I feel that I have a lot to offer any company. Due to COVID, I lost my position at ODEON as a Film Booker in the London head office. I spent the time during lockdown upskilling in modern web development and subsequently got a job as a frontend developer for a startup company, Microstrategies. I am looking for the chance to further my web development career, particularly with frontend. As I feel that I can't grow much more as a lone developer in this company, I am looking to get more experience elsewhere. Ideally, I would love to work as a React developer on web applications.

EDUCATION

Masters in Interactive Media

University of Limerick 2014-2015 1.1 first class honours

Focus on UX design, research and software skills.

Dissertation on Data Visualization

BSC Digital Media Design

University of Limerick 2010-2014 1.1 first class honours

Broad course bringing together research methodologies and design skills.

EXPERIENCE

Front End Web Developer | Oct 2020 - Present

Microstrategies Ltd - St Albans

Developing websites for clients, including Wordpress websites with WooCommerce and payment integration.

Working on in-house websites for the business, including content.

Developing applications in-house with JavaScript.

Customizing ready-made mobile apps and publishing on App Store & Google Play.

Film Booker | Aug 2019 - July 2020

ODEON Cinemas Group - London Support Office

Developing tailor-made lineups for 11 unique cinemas on a weekly basis to maximise revenue. Liaising and negotiating with film distributors and cinemas.

Data analysis and presentation, with a focus on assessing performance of ODEON sub-brands.

General office work - tracking, analysis, reports using Microsoft Office and Google Suites.

REFERENCES

Anthony Kilpatrick General Manager - Odeon Limerick +35387 4157879

<u>akilpatrick@odeonuk.com</u>

Rafal Dabrowski CTO - Microstrategies Ltd ralph@microstrategies.co.uk +44 7788 866252

OTHER EXPERIENCE/COURSES/HONOURS

Freelance Web Designer - Limerick Jazz Festival & Various

Developed Wordpress website and manage content on a yearly basis

Presentation, Direction and Production for Television Training Course

The Park Studio, Dublin (2015)

Certification in Fundamentals of Digital Marketing - Google

Awarded Scholarship for Masters in Interactive Media - 2014